# Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Email: A.F.Banaji "at" lboro.ac.uk

Website: amlan-banaji.github.io

Nationality: UK

Research Associate in Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University's mathematics department since March 2023

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My main research interests are in geometry and analysis related to fractal sets and measures. These 'fractals' exhibit complexity over a wide range of scales, and often arise in a natural dynamical way, such as via (conformal or non-conformal) iterated function systems. Currently, I am especially interested in the rate of decay of the Fourier transform of stationary measures for such systems. I have also done a lot of work exploring different ways one can define 'dimension,' to provide refined information about the global or local scaling properties of classes of sets or measures. I enjoy finding connections between these topics and other areas of mathematics such as number theory and probability theory.

## **PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS**

#### Submitted preprints:

- 11. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. Lower box dimension of infinitely generated self-conformal sets. arXiv
- 10. S. Baker and A. Banaji. Polynomial Fourier decay for fractal measures and their pushforwards. arXiv
- 9. A. Banaji, J. M. Fraser, I. Kolossváry and A. Rutar. Assouad spectrum of Gatzouras–Lalley carpets. arXiv
- 8. A. Banaji, A. Rutar and S. Troscheit. *Interpolating with generalized Assouad dimensions*. <u>arXiv</u> Published:
  - 7. A. Banaji and I. Kolossváry. *Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence*, **Advances in Mathematics** 449 (2024), 109735. *arXiv*
  - 6. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets*, **Nonlinearity** 37 (2024), 045004. <u>arXiv</u>
  - 5. A. Banaji. Generalised intermediate dimensions, Monatshefte für Mathematik 202 (2023), 465–506. arXiv
  - 4. A. Banaji. *Metric spaces where geodesics are never unique*, **American Mathematical Monthly** 130 (2023), 747–754. <u>arXiv</u>
  - 3. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors*, **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society** 376 (2023), 2449–2479. <u>arXiv</u>
  - 2. A. Banaji and H. Chen. *Dimensions of popcorn-like pyramid sets*, **Journal of Fractal Geometry** 10 (2023), 151–169. <u>arXiv</u>
  - 1. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. *Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions*, **Annales Fennici Mathematici** 47 (2022), 939–960. <u>arXiv</u>

## **EDUCATION**

University of St Andrews 2019–2023

### **PhD Mathematics**

Thesis: "Interpolating between Hausdorff and box dimension" (defended May 2023)

With the **Analysis Research Group** 

**Topic:** Fractal geometry and dimension theory

**Supervisors:** Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the **Leverhulme Trust** 

University of St Andrews 2018–2019

**MSc Mathematics, Distinction** 

**GPA**: 19.5/20. Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

#### **Dissertation:**

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College *2015–2018* 

#### **BA (Hons) Mathematics**

**Selected Part II courses:** Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

# PRIZES AND GRANTS

- 2023–4: Awarded £500 LMS Travel Grant for Early Career Researchers to visit the University of Oulu
- *2019*: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

## **TALKS**

I have given at least 40 talks (see <a href="https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf">https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf</a> ) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Invited minicourse, Focused workshop on Harmonic analysis methods in fractal geometry, Budapest, 4/11/24–8/11/24
- Fractal Geometry and Stochastics 7 (Chemnitz, 26/9/24)
- Afternoon workshop on Fourier analysis, fractals, and finite fields (invited talk, St Andrews, 18/9/24)
- Geometry and fractals under the midnight Sun (Oulu, 27/6/24)
- British Early Career Mathematicians' Colloquium (keynote talk, Birmingham, 14/6/24)
- British Mathematical Colloquium (BMC) (Manchester, 19/6/24)
- Geometric Analysis Seminar (Jyväskylä, 1/2/24)
- Fractal Geometry (celebrating Prof. Kenneth Falconer's 70th birthday, ICMS, Edinburgh, 4/7/23)
- Multifractal analysis and self-similarity (CIRM, Marseille, 30/6/23)
- <u>Diophantine Approximation, Dynamics, and Fractals</u> (Exeter, 22/6/23)
- Thermodynamic Formalism: Non-additive Aspects and Related Topics (Będlewo, 16/5/23)
- One World Fractals (online, 18/1/23)
- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium (inaugural talk, China (online), 22/10/22)
- Fractals and Related Fields IV (Porquerolles, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest, 30/6/22 and 2/9/24)

## **EXPERIENCE**

- March–May 2024: **lectured** second-year course "Elements of Topology" at Loughborough to 90 students
- Teaching undergraduate **tutorials** at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- 2018–2022: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.

## SERVICE AND MEMBERSHIPS

- 2023–present: Co-organiser of the <u>Loughborough University Dynamical Systems Seminar</u>
- 2022–present: **Referee** for Math. Ann.; Adv. Math.; Ergodic Theory Dynam. Systems; Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A; Colloq. Math.; Amer. Math. Monthly; J. Math. Anal. Appl.; Real Anal. Exchange; MathSciNet
- 2024: Co-organiser of Workshop on Ergodic Theory and Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- *2021*: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- Member of London Mathematical Society, Institute of Mathematics and its Applications